Guide to "Suits Me: The Double Life of Billy Tipton" Research and Production Records SC0608
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
"Suits Me: The Double Life of Billy Tipton" research and production records
1897-1998
bulk
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Middlebrook, Diane Wood
SC0608
8.75 Linear Feet
Research files, including interview audio recordings and transcripts; notes; correspondence; clippings; photographs; photocopies; and other materials accumulated by Diane Middlebrook in preparation for writing Suits Me: The Double Life of Billy Tipton. Also includes draft versions, page proofs, and a signed first edition of the book; correspondence with publisher Houghton-Mifflin; clippings of reviews and other publicity for the book; and correspondence received by Middlebrook in response to the book.
Separated Material
A number of published sources consulted by Middlebrook during her research for Suits Me were transferred to the university archives along with her files. Items which were available in the Stanford University Libraries general collection at the time this collection was processed were removed. A list of items removed is available in the repository. Items not held by Stanford were retained and are located at the end of Series 1.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged in five series: Series 1: Research Files; Series 2: Production Files; Series 3: Response to Book; Series 4: Photographs; and Series 5: Audio Materials. Files are arranged alphabetically within each series. Although Series 5 is closed pending preservation reformatting, a list of the audio materials it contains is available in the repository.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection consists of Middlebrook's research files, including audio recordings and transcripts of interviews; notes; correspondence; clippings; photographs; photocopies of vital records and related primary source documents; and other materials accumulated in preparation for writing Suits Me: The Double Life of Billy Tipton. The research files include a subseries of files accumulated by Gerry Everding, an Oklahoma City-based journalist who worked on the book project as a research assistant. Middlebrook's files document both Tipton's life and the local music scenes in which he participated. The subject files designated "Afterlife of Billy Tipton" contain information on other works based on Tipton's life, including several plays and musicals.
Also included are a draft of the book, page proofs, an advance reading copy, and a signed first edition; correspondence with publisher Houghton Mifflin; clippings of reviews and other publicity for the book; and correspondence received by Middlebrook in response to the book.
Biography / Administrative History
Diane Wood Middlebrook (1939-2007), biographer and longtime professor of English at Stanford University, was educated at the University of Washington (A.B., 1961) and Yale University (M.A, 1962; Ph.D., 1968). She joined the Department of English at Stanford in 1966 and remained there until 2002, when she left to focus on her writing full-time. Although she also published literary criticism and poetry, Middlebrook is best known for her biographies: Anne Sexton, A Biography (1991), Suits Me: The Double Life of Billy Tipton (1998), and Her Husband: Hughes and Plath, a Marriage (2003).
Middlebrook was approached by Kitty Oakes, the fifth and final wife of jazz musician Billy Tipton, in 1991 while on a promotional tour for Anne Sexton. Tipton's death in 1989 made international news after it was discovered that he was a woman who had been living as a man for over fifty years. Oakes proposed that Middlebrook write a book about Tipton and offered Middlebrook exclusive access to family papers and photographs. For the next several years Middlebrook conducted extensive research, including interviews with Oakes, other family members, friends, and music industry associates of Billy Tipton. The biography, titled Suits Me: The Double Life of Billy Tipton, was published by Houghton Mifflin in 1998.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Diane Wood Middlebrook, 2001.
Access
Audio recordings in box 16 are closed pending reformatting. Research files in box 17 are restricted until 2059. Other materials are open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Jazz musicians -- United States -- Biography.; Biography as a literary form.; Transgender people -- United States -- Biography.; Middlebrook, Diane Wood; Tipton, Billy
- Research Files, Series 1
  - Research logs
    - Inventory of Billy Tipton's scrapbooks and office files, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Log book, 1992 January-1995 February (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Log book, 1995 January-1996 February (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Log from binder [1 of 2], 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Log from binder [2 of 2], 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Primary sources
    - Autopsy, 1989-1996 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Birth and death certificates, 1940-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Deeds, 1893-1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Kansas City Public Schools records, 1929-1933, 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Last Will and Testament, 1965, 1982, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Letters from Billy Tipton, 1961-1968, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Letters to Billy Tipton from William T. and Doris Tipton, 1972-1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Music by Billy Tipton, Red Hair and Green Eyes, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Recording contract and correspondence, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Social security records, 1944-1987, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Stage routines, Billy Tipton, 1960-1997, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Stage routines, Billy Tipton and Kitty Kelly, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Wedding celebrations, 1957, 1962, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - People files
    - Ball, Donald, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Bamonte, Tony, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Benson, Wayne, 1994, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Brandon, Mike, 1995-1997 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Brooks, Hadda, 1995-1997 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Bruesehoff, Mary Lee, Spokane WA, 1963, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Cagle, Clarence, Tulsa OK, 1994, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Carlyle, Russ, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Cattanach, Maryann (including letters to Tipton), 1958-1995 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Clark, Doug, clippings, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Clark, Jonathan, 1978-1989, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Cox, Betty, 1989-1997 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Crews, Loretta, Nevada, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Eagle, Don, 1993, 1996, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Ellis Brower, Roberta, 1995, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Flaherty, Carrie (mother of Kitty Oakes; includes Tipton family correspondence), 1962-1986 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Fullenwider, Reggie (mother of Billy Tipton) and Lynn (includes letters to Tipton), 1910-1976 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Goodman, Benny, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Green, Jamison, 1993-1996, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Hancock, Non Earl, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Hill, Marigold, 1997, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Hollars, Mark [1 of 2], 1995 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Hollars, Mark [2 of 2] (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Jensen, Paul, 1994-1997, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Jones, Christine, photocopies of photographs, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Keithly, Gilbert, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Kilde, Ron, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Lane, Pauline, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Lee, Robert, 1994-1997 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Lent, Shirley, 1970, 1986, 1989-1997 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Mallet, Jack, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Martin, Larry and Jean Shannon, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Mayer, George, 1967-1997 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Miller, George, 1979-1995 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Murphy, Sara and Tommy Perkins [1 of 2], 1935-1997, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Murphy, Sara and Tommy Perkins [2 of 2], 1935-1997, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Oakes, Kitty, Billy Tipton tape materials, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Oakes, Kitty, correspondence [1 of 2], 1991-1996 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Oakes, Kitty, correspondence [2 of 2], 1991-1996 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Oakes, Kitty, interview notes, 1992 January (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Oakes, Kitty, interview notes, 1992 March (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Oakes, Kitty, interview transcripts, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Oakes, Kitty, interview notes, 1993 September (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Oakes, Kitty, interview notes and transcripts, 1995 January (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Oakes, Kitty, medical and school records, 1975-1977, 1992, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Oakes, Kitty, resume (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - O'Neil, Nick, 1996-1998 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Pierce, Euline, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Pearce, Euline, correspondence with Billy Tipton, 1971-1988 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Pierson, Bill (Joplin musician), 1995-1997 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Platé, René, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Pugh, Kyle, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Raines, Lewis, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Richards, Kenny and Molly, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Richter, Marv, 1985-1996 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Ronconi, Ron and Elaine, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Seaton, Jerry, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Shannon, Jean, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Spencer, Bonnie [1 of 2], 1986-1995, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Spencer, Bonnie [2 of 2], 1986-1995, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Sobol, Dave, 1993, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Stringfellow, Barron, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Swan, Katherine, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Swan, Madeline, 1994-1998 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Swan, Madeline, letters to Billy Tipton, 1975-1988 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Teagarden, Helen, information from responses to Bob Lee column, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Teagarden, Norma, 1989-1997 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Tessesnso, Ron, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Thomason, Mary Louise (Buck), 1994 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Tipton, Billy (Little Billy), 1969-1993 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Tipton, G.W. (father of Billy Tipton) and family, 1922-1994 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Tipton, G.W. and Reginald, divorce, 1927-1933, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Tipton, William T. (brother of Billy Tipton), photocopies of photographs used in book, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Tipton, William T. and Doris, 1992-1997 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Wallin, Bob, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Whitt family, information from Patty Cunningham, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Whitt, Non Earl, 1936-1994, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Whitt, Non Earl, information from J.L. Whitt, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Willis, Bryan, 1994-1995, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Wilson, Teddy, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Chronological files
    - 1914-1929 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - 1930-1934 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Kansas City newspapers, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - 1935-1939 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - 1940-1949 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Roberta Brower manuscript, 1945-1946 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - 1950-1955 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - 1956-1960 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - 1962 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - 1967-1969 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - 1971 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - 1974-1979 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - 1980-1985 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - 1986-1989 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Chronology from binder [1 of 2] (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Chronology from binder [2 of 2] (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Place files
    - Joplin, MO, 1996-1997, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Kansas City, MO, 1974, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kansas City, MO, jazz, 1929-1932 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Longview, WA, 1951, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Oklahoma [1 of 6], 1989-1995, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Oklahoma [2 of 6], 1989-1995, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Oklahoma [3 of 6], 1989-1995, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Oklahoma [4 of 6], 1989-1995, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Oklahoma [5 of 6], 1989-1995, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Oklahoma [6 of 6], 1989-1995, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Oklahoma, history, 1933, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Oklahoma, maps, 1993-1994, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Portland, OR, 1992, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Seattle, WA, 1991, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Spokane, WA [1 of 2], 1993-1995, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Spokane, WA [2 of 2], 1993-1995, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Spokane, entertainment magazines [1 of 2], 1954-1966 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Spokane, entertainment magazines [2 of 2], 1954-1966 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Subject files
    - Afterlife of Billy Tipton, 1989-1996 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Afterlife of Billy Tipton – Billy [opera], 1994 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Afterlife of Billy Tipton – Billy Tipton Memorial Saxophone Quartet, 1990-1996 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Afterlife of Billy Tipton – The Billy Tipton Story [screenplay by Kate Wright], circa 1996 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Afterlife of Billy Tipton – The Slow Drag [musical], 1997 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Afterlife of Billy Tipton – Stevie Wants to Play the Blues [play by Eduardo Machado], 1993 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Biology and Gender, clippings and photocopies, 1994-1995, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Clippings from folder marked Dave-personal re: Billy Tipton, 1989-1991 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Clippings from Kitty Oakes re: Billy Tipton (some annotated), 1989-1990 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Cross dressing and male impersonation, library search records and photocopied readings, 1996, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Cross dressing and transgender issues, clippings and photocopies, 1991-1997, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Divorce, research notes and correspondence, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Entertainment business, 1992-1996, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Freedom of Information Act request re: Billy Tipton, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - FTM Newsletter, 1987-1991 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - FTM Newsletter, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - FTM Newsletter, 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - FTM Newsletter, 1996-1997 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - FTM Newsletter, 1998-2000 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Gender, clippings and photocopies [1 of 4], 1989-1996, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Gender, clippings and photocopies [2 of 4], 1989-1996, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Gender, clippings and photocopies [3 of 4], 1989-1996, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Gender, clippings and photocopies [4 of 4], 1989-1996, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Jewel Box Revue, 1993-1995, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - NC Class of '57 reunion materials from Ron Turner, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Walkathons, Oklahoma City, clippings, 1930s (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Gerry Everding research files
    - Casper, WY, photocopies and notes, 1969-1997 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Corpus Christi, TX, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence with Middlebrook, 1996-1997 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Joplin, MO, photocopies and notes [1 of 2], 1947-1997, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Joplin, MO, photocopies and notes [2 of 2], 1947-1997, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous sources (people) – old files (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Name index leads, A-H (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Name index leads, J-N (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Name index leads, O-R (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Name index leads, S-Z (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - News articles from database search on jazz and Joplin, 1980-1996 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - News articles from database search on Tipton plus Billy, jazz, trio, etc., 1989-1996 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Notes, miscellaneous, 1994-1997 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - San Angelo, TX, notes, 1997, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Shadow Lake, manuscript by George C. Weldon [1 of 2], undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Shadow Lake, manuscript by George C. Weldon [2 of 2], undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Social security records, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Springfield, MO, 1991-1995, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Published reference sources
    - Morgan, H. Wayne and Anne Hodges Morgan. Oklahoma: A History. New York: W. W. Norton, 1984 (Box 12)
    - Olian, Joanne (ed.) Everyday Fashions of the Forties as Pictured in Sears Catalogs. New York: Dover Publications, 1992 (Box 12)
    - Oklahoma Today. Vol. 44, no. 6, November 1994-January 1995 (Box 12)
    - Ross, Jim. Oklahoma Route 66; The Cruiser's Companion. Bethany, OK: Ghost Town Press, 1992 (Box 12)
    - Sheldon, Ruth. Hubbin' It: The Life of Bob Wills., 1938 (Box 12)
    - Stewart, Roy F. Born Grown: A History of Oklahoma City. Oklahoma City: Metro Press, 1974 (Box 12)
- Production Files, Series 2
  - Correspondence with Houghton Mifflin, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Chapters 1-7 revisions, 1997 March (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Chapters 8-15 revisions, 1997 March (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript returned to Middlebrook from publisher [1 of 4], circa 1997 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript returned to Middlebrook from publisher [2 of 4], circa 1997 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript returned to Middlebrook from publisher [3 of 4], circa 1997 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript returned to Middlebrook from publisher [4 of 4], circa 1997 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Marked page proofs [1 of 3], circa 1997 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Marked page proofs [2 of 3], circa 1997 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Marked page proofs [3 of 3], circa 1997 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Photocopies of book illustrations [1 of 2] (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Photocopies of book illustrations [2 of 2] (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Dust jacket, circa 1998 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Suits Me advance reading copy, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Suits Me, first edition signed to Stanford University Libraries by Middlebrook, 1998 (Box 14)
- Response to Book, Series 3
  - Correspondence, responses to Suits Me [1 of 4], 1998 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, responses to Suits Me [2 of 4], 1998 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, responses to Suits Me [3 of 4], 1998 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, responses to Suits Me [4 of 4], 1998 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - National Public Radio All Things Considered interview of Middlebrook, transcript, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Publicity, contacts and general, 1997-1998 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Publicity for Suits Me, clippings [1 of 3], 1998 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Publicity for Suits Me, clippings [2 of 3], 1998 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Publicity for Suits Me, clippings [3 of 3], 1998 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Photographs, Series 4
  - Photograph inventories and correspondence with publisher and agent re: photographs, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Frontispiece and #1-10 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - #11-24 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - #24x-29x (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - #30-38 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - #39-48, plus unused photo D (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - #49-61, plus unused photos A, B, F, G (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - From Dave Sobol, 1955-1963, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - From Sara Murphy, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Not inventoried or used, Chapter 1: Born Naked (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Not inventoried or used, Chapter 3: Kansas City (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Not inventoried or used, Chapter 5: Graduation (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Not inventoried or used, Chapter 7: Reggie's Daughter (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Not inventoried or used, Chapter 8: Self-Made Man (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Not inventoried or used, Chapter 11: Mobility (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Not inventoried or used, Chapter 12: Making It (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Not inventoried or used, Chapter 13: Man's World (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Not inventoried or used, Chapter 14: Family Man (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Not inventoried or used, Chapter 15: Out and Down (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Carrie Flaherty family photographs, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Unsorted photographs (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Negatives from Betty Cox (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Negatives from Patty Cunningham (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Negatives from Roberta Ellis (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Negatives from Ron Kilde (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Negatives from Kitty Oakes (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Negatives from Katherine Swan (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Negatives from William T. Tipton (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Unlabeled negatives (Box 15, Folder 29)
- Audiovisual material, Series 5
  - Home Recordings
    - Billy Tipton Trio, Allen's Tin Pan Alley – Spokane, 6/16/62. Side A: Teddy Qualls – tap dancer. Side B: Ray Ball and Aggie Lee – Banjos., 1962-06-16; 16.01; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 16)
    - Cassette One. Transcription discs and 45 rpm disc. Recorded on Side A only, 16.02; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 16)
    - Cassette Two. ELKO broadcast, 12/7/55. Billy Tipton Trio at the Ranch Inn. Rec on Side A only., 1955-12-07; 16.03; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 16)
    - Cassette Three, radio broadcast of Ranch Inn, no date. Billy Tipton Trio., 16.04; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 16)
    - Cassette Four. Billy Tipton Trio rehearsal. Recorded onto Side A only., 16.05; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 16)
    - Cassette Five, 5/5/58. Billy, mother, stepfather. Idaho Falls 8/26 continued on Side B., 1958-05-05; 16.06; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 16)
    - Doe Belly and Mark Hollars[?], 7/5/95 Three cassettes., 1995-07-05; 16.07-16.09; 3 audiocassette(s) (Box 16)
    - Dubbed copy of album Positively Phranc (1991), containing song titled Tipton. Date of copy: 9/29/95., 1995-09-29; 16.1; 1 audiocassette (Box 16)
    - Dubbed copy of two Billy Tipton albums: Billy Tipton Plays Hi-Fi on the Piano and #1 Georgia Brown. Date on tape: 1989 June 12., 1989-06-12; 16.11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 16)
    - George Mayer Trio with Billy Tipton and the Shalimar Room, 1949. Transferred to cassette on 10/31/96 by the Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound from 10 and 12 transcription discs. Includes set list., 16.12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 16)
    - Middlebrook, Diane, interview on Studio Tulsa, 1998 March 4., 1998-03-04; 16.13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 16)
    - Middlebrook, Diane, interview with Terry Gross on NPR's Fresh Air, 1998 June 1., 1998-06-01; 16.14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 16)
    - Oklahoma Historical Society Archives and Manuscripts Division. Interview of Mr. Clarence Love by Joe Todd, 1983 August 1. Two cassettes. Total running time for both cassettes is 1 hour, 19 minutes., 1983-08-01; 16.15-16.16; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 16)
    - Teagarden, Norma on National Public Radio's Marian McPartland's Piano Jazz, September 1984., 1984-09; 16.17; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 16)
    - Tipton family Christmas 1974 – Merry Christmas to Grandma 1974. Little Billy, John, Scott, Kitty, Billy., 16.18; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 16)
    - Tipton family Christmas 1974 – Merry Christmas to Grandma 1974. Little Billy, John, Scott, Kitty, Billy. [Second copy with printed J-card stating Transferred to cassette by the Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound, 3/6/97. Duration ca. 20 minutes.], 16.19; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 16)
    - To Diane from the Cagles, 3/11/97, 1997-03-11; 16.2; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 16)
    - Williams, Mary Lou on National Public Radio's Marian McPartland's Piano Jazz, February 1984. With Ronnie Boykins, bass. Includes content notes., 1984-02; 16.21; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 16)
  - Commercial Recordings
    - 24 Great Hits by Bob Wills and His Texas Playboys. Polygram Records, c1977., 19 (Box 16)
    - Bob Wills: 21 Golden Hits. Highland Music, c1989., 20 (Box 16)
    - Complete Broadcast Day: 9-21-39. Radio Showcase, c1986., 21 (Box 16)
    - Remembering Billy Tipton., 1995; 22 (Box 16)
      Recorded by East Wind. All Rights Reserved, Oakes-Tipton Inc. Recorded at Bop Tech Recording Studios, Spokane WA, Michael Par. c1995. Includes recording of Billy Tipton composition Red Hair and Green Eyes.
  - Kitty Oakes Interviews
    - 1992 January 10 (Tape 1), 1992-01-10; 23; 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 16)
    - 1992 January 10 (Tape 2), 1992-01-10; 24; 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 16)
    - 1992 January 11 (Tape 3), 1992-01-11; 25; 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 16)